Paige E. Olsen

Paige.El.Olsen@Gmail.com 976 N Gibert Ct (360) 513-4178 Ridgefield, WA 98642

LinkedIn: /Paige-El-Olsen | GitHub: /POlsen-92 | Portfolio: https://polsen-92.github.io/Portfolio_2/

Summary

Front-End Developer who draws inspiration and intuitive problem solving from a unique and eclectic background. Completed a Full Stack Development Course with the University of Washington and continues to learn through websites such as CodeCademy and CodeWars as well as educational reading. Constantly driven towards expanding their education and bringing a diverse perspective to a team. Project management, problem solving and ensuring that projects are accessible to users of all needs are known strengths and passions.

Technical Skills

Languages: JavaScript ES6+, CSS3, HTML5, SQL, **Applications:** GitHub, MongoDB, MySQL, Heroku,

Tools: Express, React, Node, Handlebars, ¡Query, Bootstrap, PureCSS

Projects

Table Top App - https://table-top-fe.herokuapp.com/

December 2021

Website where D&D players can play online by creating their own campaigns, characters and interact through our community forum and play using a virtual tabletop complete with movable icons and a live chat.

Role: Full Stack Developer

Tech Used: React.js, MySQL, TinyMCE Editor, Socket.io

Collaborators: Mark Lohse-Miranda, Carsdan Dvorachek and Marco Shifflette

GitHub Link: https://github.com/POlsen-92/TableTop-FrontEnd

Manatee-Clicker Game – https://manatee-clicker.herokuapp.com/

November 2021

A simple click game where you can sign up, click for points and hire manatee bonuses to increase your click value. View your place on the leaderboard for all to see.

Role: Full Stack Developer

<u>Tech Used:</u> JavaScript, Handlebars, MySQL, Express.js, jPlayer <u>Collaborators:</u> Jonathan Newman, Chloe Harris and Jorge Barragan <u>GitHub Link:</u> https://github.com/POlsen-92/Manatee-Clicker

Exercise App - https://polsen-92.github.io/WorkOut_Generator_App/

October 2021

A versatile, clean, and helpful website where you can choose from a wide selection of areaspecific exercises to make your best daily workout.

Role: Front End Developer

Tech Used: JavaScript, HTML, Pure CSS

Collaborators: Mark Lohse-Miranda, Muhammed Abbasi and Melyssa Dennis

GitHub Link: https://github.com/Willowsmith/ExerciseIsFun

Education

University Of Washington – Full-Stack Coding Bootcamp Certificate

• Washington State University – B.S. Biology

• Washington State University – B.S. Nutrition and Exercise Physiology

Codecademy Certifications

Learn JavaScript
Learn jQuery
Learn CSS
Learn CSS
Learn CSS
Learn CSS
Learn CSS
Learn Async JavaScript
October 2021
Learn Async JavaScript

Work Experience

Crunch Fitness Vancouver Plaza - Vancouver, Washington

October 2018-July 2021

Graduation: December 2021

Graduation: December 2020

Graduation: May 2016

Personal Trainer at Crunch Fitness where I work with clients to improve mobility and function

Some of my clients present with extreme mobility challenges which I've assisted in improving such as a complete knee dislocation and a traumatic car injury resulting in almost 30 broken bones.

Legacy Meridian Park Medical Center – Tualatin, Oregon

January 2017-May 2017

Cardiopulmonary Intern for the Outpatient Cardiopulmonary Clinic. During my 6-month internship I completed 440 hours with tasks ranging from assisting classes to interpreting rhythms, taking blood pressures, blood glucose, completing six-minute walk tests, exercise classes and as an internship project I implemented a class using inspiratory muscle training devices for pulmonary patients.

United States Army Reserves – Vancouver, Washington

October 2015-December 2017

68M- Nutrition Care Specialist for the Army Reserves stationed out of Vancouver, Washington at the rank of specialist. Duties at drill include working with a dietitian, 1LT Lopez-Stickney to plan and prepare lunch for the entire company as well as work with soldiers who need to lose weight on their nutrition and exercise habits.